<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Afito Blogs]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog focusing on the state of college housing.]]></description><link>localhost:8000/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 01:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Top Landlords at SUNY Cortland]]></title><description><![CDATA[Searching around to find great landlords at SUNY Cortland can be a time-consuming task, especially if you’re moving off campus for the first…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//top-landlords-at-suny-cortland/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//top-landlords-at-suny-cortland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Searching around to find great landlords at SUNY Cortland can be a time-consuming task, especially if you’re moving off campus for the first time. No one wants to find themselves in a less than desirable living situation while working their way through school. Thankfully, we at Afito have gotten to know almost every college landlord in the area. Here’s our list of the best landlords at SUNY Cortland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/252&quot;&gt;Gary Baccile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary Baccile has been renting to students in the Cortland area for the past eight years. With the help of his maintenance specialist Kip Fox, who has over thirty years of experience in property management, Gary owns and manages seven student rentals around town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/253&quot;&gt;Ithacor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ithacor is a local property management company serving Cortland as well as several other cities and towns in the area. They work with area property owners to manage their rental houses efficiently and effectively, and have over fifteen years of experience in the space. They are well known for being responsive and accommodating to tenant concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/224&quot;&gt;Calabro Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calabro Properties offers many housing options to student tenants, all of which are a quick walk to campus and downtown. Single person one bedroom apartments all the way up to houses for large groups of 9+ students are available. Each and every apartment is fully furnished and recently renovated, with such amenities as flat screen televisions, in-unit laundry facilities, and snow removal services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/275&quot;&gt;SV Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SV Student rentals is an experienced SUNY Cortland student landlord offering everything from small one bedroom apartments to large 12 bedroom houses. Each property is located within walking distance from campus and downtown. All units are fully furnished and feature included garbage pickup, parking, laundry, and high speed internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/233&quot;&gt;Marc Pace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Pace has been renting to Cortland students for more than 25 years! Marc takes pride in his houses and has each one refurbished and professionally inspected every year. All of his properties are a short walk to campus. Tenants tend to be very happy with Marc and feel that he goes above and beyond as a landlord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/237&quot;&gt;Cortland Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Student Rentals, owned and operated by Mark’s brother Keith Pace, has been managing off-campus housing in Cortland since 1979. They take pride in being a local landlord and improving the community in which they live and do business. Tenants can expect a responsive landlord with people on-call around the clock. All units are well furnished and close by to campus and downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/225&quot;&gt;Michael Pace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not often that you see three brothers at the same school offering great student rental properties. Michael Pace brings forty years of experience in student housing to his properties at Cortland. All units are fully furnished and feature free parking and snow/trash removal. Utilities are included in the rent for most units!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/247&quot;&gt;Paradigm Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradigm Properties has been in the SUNY Cortland off campus housing business since 1981. The company strives to provide the highest quality student housing, and pays particular attention to the smart design of its units for student tenants. Paradigm maintains a full-time property manager and maintenance staff and is on call around the clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/232&quot;&gt;Armideo Student Housing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The father-son team behind Armideo Student Housing offers a large number of great student housing options in the Cortland area. Joe Armideo has been renting to students since 1972 and boasts that if your parents went to Cortland, he probably knew them. Apartments feature on-site laundry and new kitchen and bathroom facilities, and parking and snow removal are included in the rent. Unlike some area landlords, Armideo Student Housing allows for rent to be paid monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/246&quot;&gt;Cortland Off Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serving the SUNY Cortland and TC3 communities for over 30 years, Cortland Off Campus offers some of the best student rentals around. Units are close by to campus as well as downtown and are fully furnished (including with leather couches and large flat-screen televisions.) 24/7 staff are available around the clock for every tenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/288&quot;&gt;Collegetown Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collegetown Rentals offers many student rental properties at SUNY Cortland, each close by to campus, downtown, and the athletic complexes. All units are fully furnished and feature all-in rental rates which include utilities, laundry, and snow removal. Maintenance staff are on call 24/7 to respond to any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/278&quot;&gt;Walk2Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk2Campus has been providing off campus housing since 2004. They strive to maintain beautiful rental units within walking distance to campus and are particularly proud of their values-driven approach to property management. Walk2Campus is committed to leaving a positive impact on the environment and using the most sustainable methods possible to operate their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/279&quot;&gt;RMP Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RMP Properties has been in the Cortland off campus housing business since 2003. RMP strives to make student tenants’ lives as easy as possible by providing affordable and all inclusive rental properties. All units are close to campus and are designed to have a positive impact on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/301&quot;&gt;JE Management Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JE Management group provides a variety of houses and apartments near SUNY Cortland and TC3. With over twenty years experience in the business, student tenants can rest assured that they will have an easy leasing and renting experience with JE Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/280&quot;&gt;Working on a Dream Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living by the motto “You work on your dream…we work on the rest,” Working on a Dream Properties provides affordable, high quality student housing just a short walk from campus and downtown. The company features an on-call local manager as well as included utilizes for all units. Working on a Dream places a specific emphasis on providing clean and well-maintained houses and apartments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the unlikely event that you can’t find your home away from home from these outstanding landlords in the SUNY Cortland area, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/area/6&quot;&gt;check out Afito&lt;/a&gt; to see the rest of the available listings near campus. If you would prefer living in an apartment building, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.afito.com/best-apartments-for-cortland-students/&quot;&gt;check out our article on the best apartments for Cortland students.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Best Apartments For Cortland Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[We all know that finding a great off campus apartment can be a hassle. But don’t worry! Lucky for you we’ve already done a lot of the…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//best-apartments-for-cortland-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//best-apartments-for-cortland-students/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We all know that finding a great off campus apartment can be a hassle. But don’t worry! Lucky for you we’ve already done a lot of the research on your behalf. Behold the top student apartments in the Cortland area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/246&quot;&gt;Cortland Off Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, three, and four bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Off Campus has been managing student rentals around SUNY Cortland for more than 30 years. Their buildings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/534&quot;&gt;90 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/545&quot;&gt;19 W. Court St&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/537&quot;&gt;88 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt; offer well-managed, fully furnished, and conveniently located places to live for Cortland students. Cortland Off Campus also owns and manages several smaller buildings and single family homes that are also available as student rentals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/602&quot;&gt;8 Lincoln Ave.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right in the middle of the action in downtown Cortland and a super quick walk to campus, 8 Lincoln Ave. is a unique apartment building with a community feel. Perfect for students moving out of the dorms, this building features plenty of parking as well as free utilities and WiFi. The building is owned and managed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/275&quot;&gt;SV Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;, a well-established Cortland landlord that also rents many smaller buildings and homes in the area to student tenants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/257&quot;&gt;Cornerstone Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cornerstone Properties, a 35 year veteran of the Cortland residential housing market, offers new and spacious three bedroom suites at several locations around Cortland, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/570&quot;&gt;112 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/575&quot;&gt;100 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/573&quot;&gt;50 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/574&quot;&gt;52 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/571&quot;&gt;7 Woodruff St.&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/572&quot;&gt;91 Lincoln Ave.&lt;/a&gt;. All of these locations are a walkable distance from campus and downtown. Units are fully furnished and include free WiFi and parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/634&quot;&gt;41 Prospect Terrace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two and three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;41 Prospect Terrace, owned by the aptly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/299&quot;&gt;Campus Side Apartments LLC&lt;/a&gt;, is as close to campus as you can get. The building features fully renovated and fully furnished two and three bedroom apartments that are just a quick walk to downtown Cortland. 41 Prospect is a perfect option for students moving out of the dorms who want to stay as close as possible to everything happening on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/632&quot;&gt;College Suites at Cortland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, three, and four bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College Suites at Cortland is a new building jam-packed with luxury amenities, located just outside the city of Cortland. Just a few minutes drive from downtown, College Suites features free parking, media rooms, fitness centers, game rooms, and a basketball court. The brand new apartments are fully furnished and come with free WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/631&quot;&gt;Cortland Park Apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, and three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located just across the Tioughnioga River at 44 Rickard St., Cortland Park Apartments is a beautiful apartment complex featuring a relaxing outdoor pool and over five acres of beautifully maintained grounds, as well as tennis and basketball courts. Just 5 minutes from SUNY Cortland and a quick walk into downtown, Cortland Park is a perfect option for students looking for beautiful surroundings and a quieter living arrangement that is still close to all the happenings downtown and on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/628&quot;&gt;Village Terrace&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/627&quot;&gt;Country Townhomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located just outside the city of Cortland, these adjacent apartment complexes feature a beautiful park-like setting that is just a quick stroll away from the Professional Studies Building and the athletics fields. These homey units are perfect for serious students seeking a quieter place to live. Both complexes are owned by Cortland-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/282&quot;&gt;DLH Properties&lt;/a&gt;, which has been operating in the area since 1989.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/633&quot;&gt;Cortland Campus View&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Campus View at 211 Tompkins Street is a charming building featuring three bedroom apartments that is situated right across the street from SUNY Cortland. The building is very close to the School of Professional Studies, the Stadium Complex, and Lusk Fieldhouse, making it an excellent choice for student athletes and professional studies students. Units are fully furnished and feature free WiFi and utilities included in the cost of rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/629&quot;&gt;Stevens Manor Apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stevens Manor Apartments at 10 Homestead Drive offers affordable one and two bedroom units that are a quick walk to the athletics fields and Professional Studies building. Perfect for athletes and professional studies students, Stevens Manor offers some of the most affordable rents in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this information will help make your hunt for off campus student housing at SUNY Cortland a bit easier. If you’re still having trouble finding your perfect home, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/area/6&quot;&gt;click here to see what’s available around campus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Tips for Picking the Perfect Off-Campus Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Picking an off-campus apartment is not an easy task. There are lots of factors that you need to take into consideration when making this…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//5-tips-for-picking-the-perfect-off-campus-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//5-tips-for-picking-the-perfect-off-campus-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Picking an off-campus apartment is not an easy task. There are lots of factors that you need to take into consideration when making this type of decision because one wrong move could cost you hundreds of extra dollars a month. And nobody wants that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is we’ve put together 5 tips for picking the perfect off-campus apartment so you can enjoy these fun (and hopefully, educational!) years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. First, Make a Budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you even start looking for an apartment, the first thing you should do is make a budget of what you can afford to pay for rent each month. One of the biggest mistakes students make when signing their first lease is getting something they can’t afford. The last thing you want to worry about is scraping up enough money each month to make rent. Be proactive, find out what you’re able to spend each month, and stick to it! You may not get the gorgeous apartment of your dreams on a college budget, but a smaller apartment or an extra few minutes walk to campus is probably better than going a year without any spending money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Take Some Tours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t just look at one apartment or housing unit. Take the time to set up multiple apartment tours and have a clear understanding of what options you have. Our advice: pick your top three off-campus living options and go tour them all. That way when it comes time to make a decision, you’ve seen everything firsthand and won’t have to worry about any surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Location, Location, Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a student means you need to spend a lot of time on campus. Whether you’re studying in the library, taking classes, or just hanging out with friends, much of your time will be spent there. So location is an important factor to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s not located within walking distance of your class buildings, is there a bus stop nearby that can take you to class? What about other transportation opportunities? Make sure that no matter where you end up you have an easy, convenient and hopefully free way to get where you need to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Grab Some Roomies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If at all possible, get some roommates. Living with other college students can make rent and utilities cheaper and more affordable. Find people who are looking for a similar living situation as you are and find a place together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When signing a lease, make sure everyone is there and that everyone signs the lease. Depending on your lease agreement you want to make sure that if someone breaks the lease that they can be held accountable for their share of the rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Read Your Lease, Seriously!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of leases, before signing your name- read the lease! Your name is going on a legal document which means that you can be held liable for violating any of its provbisions. Take the fifteen minutes to read the lease, make sure you understand it, and then sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, make a budget, shop around, pay attention to the location, get some roommates, and read your lease. There you go- 5 simple things that you can do to help make your apartment hunting experience easier and more successful. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Things You Need to Know Before Signing a Lease for an Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s say you’re speaking with an owner of an off-campus apartment complex. Everything sounds great and the apartment is in decent shape…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//3-things-you-need-to-know-before-signing-a-lease-for-an-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//3-things-you-need-to-know-before-signing-a-lease-for-an-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’re speaking with an owner of an off-campus apartment complex. Everything sounds great and the apartment is in decent shape, then the owner turns to you and asks “Do you have any questions?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if you’re a first-time apartment hunter, knowing what questions to ask in these situations can be tricky. Lucky for you, we’ve got a list of the top questions to ask a landlord before agreeing to sign a lease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“What, exactly, is included in my rent?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, you want to know what you’re paying for. To make the right decision on an apartment, you need to have a clear understanding of what’s included in your rent. Are there any utilities included in your rent (water, heat, electricity, etc.)? What about amenities? Do you get free access to a clubhouse or workout room with your rent costs? What about parking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might surprise you how much is actually included in your rent costs, so it’s important that you ask the question. It can really influence your decision one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also find it helpful to have a set of things written out that you want or need your rent to cover. (For example, you might need in-house laundry facilities or a garage space for your car, or you might really want a gym/exercise room). If the owner doesn’t mention something on your list, ask about it and see if that’s an additional cost you will have to pick up somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“How much does the average utility bill cost?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to think that when you sign a lease to an apartment, the only cost you have to worry about paying is rent. While rent is the main cost, you will also need to keep in mind that you will have to pay a monthly utility bill as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the area, the time of year, the size of the apartment, and the energy efficiency of its appliances (oh, and how good you are at turning off the lights!) utility bills can range from as low as $20 to as high as $100. The only way to really get a feel for what you might have to pay is to ask apartment owner what the average utility bill costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Are there any additional fees?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a college student, you are typically living on a tight budget as it is. You’re going to want to make sure that there won’t be any extra fees that pop up. Ask the owner if there will be a signing fee, processing/application fee, subleasing fee, approval fee or anything else. Be on the lookout for fees like these because it can add up quickly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, these questions will help you in your decision-making process and give you a better idea of what you want from an apartment or housing unit. Best of luck with your apartment search!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[4 Important Apartment Hunting Tips for Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[Renting your first off-campus apartment is an exciting milestone, but it can also be a huge source of stress if you are unprepared. Whether…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//4-important-apartment-hunting-tips-for-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//4-important-apartment-hunting-tips-for-students/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Renting your first off-campus apartment is an exciting milestone, but it can also be a huge source of stress if you are unprepared. Whether you are moving out of your parents’ house or seeking alternatives to on-campus housing, there are several things you should know before you begin your student housing search. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Your Search Early&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-Campus housing can be the best student housing option for many, but it can be difficult to find off-campus apartments if you’re not proactive in your search. It is recommended to start your search for student housing 8-12 months in advance for areas with a highly competitive rental market. For areas that are not as competitive, 2-6 months is recommended. Begin your student housing search as early as possible to avoid competing with other students seeking off-campus living arrangements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take Advantage of Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure where to begin your search for student housing, there are several resources available. First, check if &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com&quot;&gt;Afito.com&lt;/a&gt; has listings for your school — Afito only lists rentals designed for students. If your school isn’t on there, that’s okay too. Most universities offer off-campus living services. It is also possible to find local listings in the newspaper or by driving around campus looking for rental signs. However, the best place to begin your student housing search is online. If your school isn’t on &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com&quot;&gt;Afito.com&lt;/a&gt;, other listing sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zillow.com&quot;&gt;Zillow.com&lt;/a&gt; may have some student housing options and can connect you with landlords near your school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plan Your Budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for student housing, consider your living costs to see whether the rent will fit into your budget. This way, you won’t make the mistake of signing a lease on an apartment you can’t afford. The general rule of thumb is that your monthly income should be three times your monthly rent, although your situation may be different depending on if you receive aid from your parents or other sources.
If affordable student housing is your goal, planning your budget in advance is an effective way to determine if off-campus living is right for you. Planning your budget before your student housing search can help you decide where you can cut costs and how many roommates you will need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Distance is Key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proximity to campus can greatly affect the cost of rent. The closer to campus a property is, the higher the rent is likely going to be. If you have access to a vehicle, the best option for affordable student housing is looking for properties in neighboring towns. Living just 10-15 minute from campus can save you up to hundreds a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also take into account your daily commute; your distance from classes and other on-campus activities can greatly affect your experience with off-campus living. If you can find an off-campus apartment within walking distance from classes, a grocery store, and anything else you will need, you can forgo the added cost of fuel or car insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On-Campus VS Off-Campus Housing]]></title><description><![CDATA[College is different for everybody and your experience will greatly differ depending on where you choose to live. While some may prefer the…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//on-campus-vs-off-campus-housing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//on-campus-vs-off-campus-housing/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;College is different for everybody and your experience will greatly differ depending on where you choose to live. While some may prefer the community aspect of living on-campus, others may prefer the independence of living off-campus. When looking at student housing options, the choice you make can affect your entire college experience, therefore it’s important to consider the best student housing options for your situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living in on-campus housing&lt;/strong&gt; can be a great way to build your social circle and be involved in campus life.  In most cases, you will be in close proximity to everything else on campus such as: your classes, the dining hall, libraries, and the student center. Most campuses also provide transportation services that make it easy to get around campus. On-campus housing is often considered to be the best option for incoming freshmen and is sometimes mandated by the school for underclassmen.
However, for most on-campus housing options, there are rules and regulations you have to follow. Infringement of these rules can often lead to suspension or expulsion from the residence hall or even the university. On top of strict regulations, campus housing can often be expensive and may not be the most affordable student housing option. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living off-campus&lt;/strong&gt; is a great idea for those seeking more private student housing options and can be an attractive alternative for those seeking independence from the commotion of campus life. Off-campus housing is often cheaper than living on-campus and is the best student housing option for upperclassmen who wish to focus on their studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for off-campus living arrangements it’s important to consider the safety of the neighborhood as well as the proximity to campus. It’s also important to know what to look for in a landlord when looking at off-campus housing options. Because off-campus housing isn’t owned by the school, make sure to be aware of local ordinances and other regulations set by the township. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While off-campus housing can seem like the easy choice, it comes with responsibilities. On top of rent and utilities, renters generally spend more time grocery-shopping, preparing meals, cleaning, and commuting. Despite these obligations, living off-campus offers even more freedom than you would get from living in a residence hall. At the same time, it helps with the transition to life after college by acclimating you to responsibilities like house maintenance, rent, and other bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both on- and off-campus housing have their benefits and drawbacks. It’s up to you to weigh the pros and cons and figure out the best student housing option for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Get the Most Out of Your Afito Listing]]></title><description><![CDATA[The way landlords advertise their rental properties has changed a lot over the past decade. Fortunately for today’s property owners, in 201…]]></description><link>localhost:8000//how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-afito-listing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000//how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-afito-listing/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The way landlords advertise their rental properties has changed a lot over the past decade. Fortunately for today’s property owners, in 2019 this process can be as easy as posting your vacancies on a popular listing platform. College landlords however need to be especially mindful of the expectations prospective student tenants have when searching for their off-campus home. Here are a few pointers on how to separate your listing from the rest of the pack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your main photo is your first impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting clear, high quality photographs of the front of your rentals is the first step to a great listing. Listings with visually appealing, high-resolution photographs tend to catch students’ attention as they scroll through potential homes and apartments. Don’t balk at hiring a professional to photograph your properties- the expense is likely to pay dividends for years to come whenever you advertise vacancies online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The more pictures, the better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students want to see as many high quality pictures as they can when researching housing options. College tenants like to see pictures that reflect a properties cleanliness as well as its physical features. If you don’t currently have photographs of the interiors of your properties, we recommend having them taken (or taking them yourself) the next time your leases turn over, before your new tenants move in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thorough Descriptions are key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students want to know as much as possible before reaching out to a landlord. If information about a listing is lacking, many prospective tenants will simply move on to a more informative listing. Some topics students love to see in listing descriptions are: what amenities are offered, what kind of parking is available, whether any bills or utilities are included, and details about the occupancy of the house (how many singles, doubles, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strike a professional tone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College kids, who are usually new to living on their own, want responsive, reliable landlords that they feel will ensure a smooth and pleasant off-campus living experience. Student tenants respond well to landlords who are organized, respond quickly to inquiries, and take care to communicate in a professional and friendly matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Placement matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No surprises here- students are more likely to see and respond to listings that appear at the top of the listing search feed. Afito offers an innovative premium listings leaderboard that allows landlords to pay a monthly fee to launch their listing to the top ranks of the search results for their University. While this is a great way to increase exposure, landlords must be mindful that getting your property to the top is only half the battle- the listing itself must be attractive to your audience in order for them to click on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Afito team is happy to help our customers improve the quality and reach of their listings. If you need help, or have other any questions or concerns, shoot us an email at support@afito.com. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>