<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Afito Blogs]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog focusing on the state of college housing.]]></description><link>localhost:8000</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 14:23:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Should You Have a Pet at College? Pet-Friendly Apartments and Tips]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do you love pets? You’re not alone! About 68% of American households have one or more pets—that’s about 85 million pet-owning households…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/should-you-have-a-pet-at-college-pet-friendly-apartments-and-tips/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/should-you-have-a-pet-at-college-pet-friendly-apartments-and-tips/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Do you love pets? You’re not alone! About 68% of American households have one or more pets—that’s about 85 million pet-owning households. Maybe you’ve had small pets your whole life and can’t imagine life without them. Maybe you don’t want to leave your beloved dog or cat behind. Or maybe, you find that having an emotional support animal greatly improves your mental and physical wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get it! It’s tough to consider colleges knowing that you’ll likely have to leave your pets behind. With that in mind, here’s what you need to know if you want to have a pet at college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Most Residence Halls Don’t Allow Any Pets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some residence halls will let you have an aquatic pet in a small tank… think a betta fish or hermit crab. Others are even stricter and won’t allow any pets at all. College campuses aren’t trying to be cruel with these rules. They’re just trying to keep everyone’s best interest in mind—both students and pets—while also ensuring that residence halls remain clean, safe places to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. There Are Pet-Friendly Apartments Near Most Campuses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pets usually aren’t allowed in dorms or student residence halls, but that’s not a problem if you’re willing to live off campus! There are often pet-friendly places to live near campuses. Some of these apartments, condos or houses will be dog and cat friendly. Others only allow small pets, so you could potentially get a hamster, bird, or other small animal. And some will allow emotional support animals if they are truly needed and if they are well behaved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Pets May Be Able to Visit. Check Your College’s Rules.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you family comes to visit you on weekends, they might be able to bring the family pet along… but make sure to check the rules. They may or may not be able to bring pets into the residence halls, even for a few minutes. If pets are not allowed on campus even for visits, check for a nearby pet-friendly café or park where you can play with your pet when they come to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. If You Still Can’t Have a Pet, Try Volunteering at a Shelter!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every community has animal shelters and rescue groups that welcome volunteers. Find the nearest Humane Society, rescue group, or volunteer organization near your campus and see what it takes to become a volunteer. Walking the dogs at the shelter could give you some exercise, allow you to help out the community, and fulfill your need for canine cuddles!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Having a Pet Can Improve Your Quality of Life, But It Can Also Be a Ton of Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carefully consider whether it’s truly a good idea to have a pet at college. You’ll be busy with classes, studying, and other activities. A demanding pet, like a dog, is usually not the best choice for a college student. A small pet that’s less demanding might be a better option if you really think you need a pet at college. Be 100% sure that you can properly care for the pet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaning up after it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying for its vet care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buying it what it needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving it the attention it needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that being said, it’s up to you! Find pet-friendly places to live near your college campus at &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/&quot;&gt;Afito&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Moving Out of State? Here's How to Make It Go Smoothly!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you attending college out of state? Good for you! There are so many amazing things about moving across the country for college. You get…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/moving-out-of-state-heres-how-to-make-it-go-smoothly/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/moving-out-of-state-heres-how-to-make-it-go-smoothly/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Are you attending college out of state? Good for you! There are so many amazing things about moving across the country for college. You get to experience a new place and new people. Exciting possibilities await! But the whole process of moving long-distance can be rough. There are lots of logistics involved when you’re packing up your things to move out to school for the year. So, here are some tips for moving across the country, stress-free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Try to Travel Light&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have a lot of stuff? That could be a problem if you’re moving across the country, especially if you’ll be living in a dorm room or a small apartment. Moving more stuff costs way more money if you’re using a moving service. It can also be more stressful trying to fit everything. So, if you can, try to travel light. Leave some things at home if possible, donate what you don’t need, and buy new household items when you get to your new city instead of buying them before you leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Package Everything Securely&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been guilty of just throwing stuff in the back of the car and hitting the road, but if you really want a low-stress and organized move, then you’ll definitely want to get some boxes, pack your items in an organized way, and label everything so you know what’s where. This becomes more important if you’re moving across the country. Things need to be well-packaged to ensure they reach their destination safe and undamaged. This is especially important for fragile items, like TVs or computers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Keep the Essentials With You&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s anything you really don’t want to lose, or something that you’ll need right away, you need to keep it with you. Moving trucks and shipping services can get delayed, and you don’t want to be caught without your most important items. Maybe you’re traveling by car, or maybe you’re flying out to your new university. No matter how you’re traveling, you should keep your essentials close by! This might include hygiene products, a few sets of clothes, your laptop, chargers, and any valuable/important belongings that you might be bringing to college with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Double-Check Your Scheduling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to coordinate your moving truck or package arrival with your move-in date. Double-check with your landlord and the movers/shipping service to make sure you’ll have keys and access to the new place by the time you and your stuff get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Use Checklists to Your Advantage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always a good idea to make a list of everything you need and everything you’re planning to bring. This accomplishes a few things: it makes it less likely that you’ll forget items back home and it gives you an idea of how much stuff you have (which is useful if you’re packing up a vehicle or hiring a moving service).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Off-Campus Housing at Texas Tech: Is It the Right Choice for You?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you attending TTU this upcoming semester? Whether you’re an incoming freshman, a transfer student, or a current Texas Tech student, you…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/off-campus-housing-at-texas-tech-is-it-the-right-choice-for-you /</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/off-campus-housing-at-texas-tech-is-it-the-right-choice-for-you /</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Are you attending TTU this upcoming semester? Whether you’re an incoming freshman, a transfer student, or a current Texas Tech student, you’re probably looking for a place to live. There are countless options when it comes to both on-campus and off-campus housing for Red Raiders like you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Campus Housing at Texas Tech: Pros and Cons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TTU offers several opportunities to live on campus. Some of the upsides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TTU has been named one of the safest and most secure college campuses in the nation. It’s also been named among the most affordable campuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They offer suite-style residence halls, apartments, and traditional dorm rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can join a Learning Community with other students in your major.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get a meal program to make it easy to grab a bite to eat before and after classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are some of the downsides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choices are limited and you may not be able to choose your location. Some dorms are better than others, and you may get the short end of the stick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may not be able to choose your roommate, especially if you’re a new student. You might end up with a random roommate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re subject to all on-campus rules, including no alcohol, no vaping, no pets, no candles, courtesy hours/quiet hours, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are strict traffic and parking regulations. A campus parking permit will cost you extra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: If you’re a new Raider with under 30 college credit hours, you’re required to live in residence halls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Off-Campus Housing at Texas Tech: Pros and Cons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, onto the off-campus housing! If you’re eligible to live off-campus, we strongly encourage it for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get a ton of choice as to where to live and who to live with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’ll still get to live close to campus. You might even be closer to your classes than some of the dorms would be!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many off-campus residences have free parking or parking spaces included in your rent, along with more parking for your guests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on your landlord and rental contract, rules will likely be more relaxed than they would be on campus. For example, you may be able to have pets!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Off-campus residences are often located near fun bars, restaurants, coffee shops, and other hangout spots—so you’ll have plenty of options to hang out with friends and grab a bite to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Off-campus residences are often closer to grocery stores/shopping, so you can purchase what you need without hitching a ride or buying from expensive shops on campus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, some of the potential downsides of living off campus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You won’t be able to live in a Learning Community with other students in your major, which could make it harder to arrange study groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on where you live, you might have to walk farther to get to class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still trying to decide whether you want to live in Texas Tech University student housing or in an apartment off campus? Feel free to browse our &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/off-campus-housing/texas-tech-university&quot;&gt;200+ listings at TTU today to see your many options for off-campus housing at Texas Tech!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Living Off-Campus at the University of Washington!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you planning to go to school at the University of Washington in Seattle, WA? Or are you a current student who is thinking of moving off…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/living-off-campus-at-the-university-of-washington/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/living-off-campus-at-the-university-of-washington/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to go to school at the University of Washington in Seattle, WA? Or are you a current student who is thinking of moving off campus? This is the article you need if you’re still trying to figure out where to live! We’ll discuss the types of student housing you can find here in Seattle, the average prices, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Deciding Where to Live Off Campus in Seattle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are a few things to keep in mind whenever you’re living off campus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location—&lt;/b&gt;not just the distance to campus, but also the distance to the store, your friend’s residences, and popular hangout spots like bars and coffee shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Budget—&lt;/b&gt;how much can you afford to spend each month?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Number of bedrooms and bathrooms—&lt;/b&gt;chances are, you will need one or more roommates, so how many rooms do you need in order to afford the apartment without being overcrowded?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Personal preferences—&lt;/b&gt;would you prefer to live in a high-rise apartment? A house? A pet-friendly place? Something modern, or something with historical charm?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Cost of Living Off-Campus at the U of W in Seattle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of living off-campus depends on a lot of factors: how many roommates are living in the apartment or house? How luxurious is the apartment? How many bedrooms and bathrooms are there? What is the location? And, how much will utilities (like electricity, water and internet) cost? So, it’s tough to give an estimate of how much you’ll spend each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in a modest house or apartment with several roommates, you may be spending $200 or so month—that’s with utilities factored in.  If you want to live alone, with only one roommate, or in a nice house or apartment, you could easily spend upwards of $1000—though, we understand that’s out of reach for many college students’ budgets!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Finding the Right Place for You with Afito&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use a website like Afito.com to help you find your new apartment at the University of Washington in Seattle, you’ll be able to filter by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home type (apartment, house, studio, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of bedrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of bathrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can help you narrow down the search! Plus, there’s a helpful map that gives you a visual idea of where everything is located in relation to the university and other landmarks in Seattle.
You can even mark a property as a “favorite” so you can compare and contrast later. Share with your roommates as you’re house hunting—or send your favorites to your friends and see if they want to be your roommates, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afito is unique because it’s specifically made to help students like you who are searching for off-campus housing! In addition to searching on Afito, it never hurts to ask around to see if anyone you know has a place in mind that would work for your needs. Sometimes, word of mouth is a great way to find the perfect place to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/off-campus-housing/university-of-washington&quot;&gt;We’ve listed more than 250 homes and apartments for rent to choose from at UW at Seattle&lt;/a&gt;. Check them out today—you might just find exactly what you’re looking for!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Manage Your Money While Living Off Campus]]></title><description><![CDATA[It may be a stereotype, but for so many people, it’s true: college students are often low on funds. College is expensive. And, with…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/how-to-manage-your-money-while-living-off-campus/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/how-to-manage-your-money-while-living-off-campus/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It may be a stereotype, but for so many people, it’s true: college students are often low on funds. College is expensive. And, with countless hours spent studying and attending classes, there’s limited time available for you to work. Most college jobs don’t pay in the millions, so you’re stuck on a budget for the time being. But don’t worry! We’re here with tips to help you manage your money while still having a comfortable place to live. You can live well and keep things affordable at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Choose a living situation that you can afford.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you opt to live in an apartment, share a house with housemates, or even live on campus in the dorms, be absolutely sure that you can afford your living situation. This is your biggest monthly expense and you can’t get away with simply not paying your rent. If money is tight, you will probably need to choose a cheaper living situation or get another roommate/housemate.
But, do your best to balance this with your own convenience and safety. Don’t live in an unsafe apartment or choose one that’s prohibitively far away from conveniences. You can browse Afito based on price to find an affordable apartment that fits in your budget and has the amenities you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Track your spending.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know it sounds boring, but the best way to get a handle on your spending is to track everything. Whether you use an app or decide to write it all out on paper, tracking your spending helps you understand where your money is going so you can budget better. It might sound like a chore, but it can REALLY pay off—not just now, but all throughout your life! And with an app linked to your bank account, it’s really not that hard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Get good at shopping for deals.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, you will have to spend money, even when money is tight. There are everyday necessities: clothing, household items, food. And obviously, you want to have fun sometimes, whether that means going to a movie, ordering pizza with friends, or buying yourself something that you really want. So, no matter what you’re buying, try to find a good deal. Buy your groceries when they’re on sale. Shop the thrift store for clothes and home furnishings. Again, this is a great skill that will be beneficial for the rest of your life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Don’t overuse credit cards!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millions of people fall into the trap of overusing credit cards each year. Don’t fall into this trap! A credit card might seem like the perfect way to tide you over until you get more money. But this often isn’t the case. Only charge as much as you know you can pay off. You don’t want to start your adult life out in debt. However, it’s OK to use a credit card for some purchases, because it’ll help you build credit that will be beneficial when you go to buy a car or even a home.
We hope these money tips help you out as you go through college and prepare for the rest of your life!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Reasons You Should Live Off Campus]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you’re trying to find a place to live, it’s very important that your landlord sees you as a good renter (aka tenant)! Unfortunately…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/5-reasons-you-should-live-off-campus/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/5-reasons-you-should-live-off-campus/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you’re trying to find a place to live, it’s very important that your landlord sees you as a good renter (aka tenant)! Unfortunately, there are landlords out there who don’t like to rent to college students. They may see students as irresponsible, messy, or prone to being late on rent payments. But you can prove them wrong with these tips on how to be a good renter! Bonus—you’ll get your security deposit back at the end of your lease term!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #1: Understand the Lease&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to read through the lease in order to understand it. Make sure you know the rules involved. Are pets prohibited? Don’t bring pets into your apartment. Do you have to take trash to the curb every Tuesday? Make sure to do that! Not allowed to have noisy parties? Go to the bar instead, or have a party at a friend’s house if their apartment allows it. Understand what is and isn’t allowed, and follow these rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you break the terms of the lease, you will show your landlord that you’re untrustworthy. If that happens, they’ll be less likely to be lenient if you mess up in the future. You may also have to pay hefty fines for breaking the rules. Worst case scenario: Breaking the terms of your lease could even lead to you being asked to leave your apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #2: Pay Your Rent on Time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice in your contract that you have to pay your rent by a certain date or you’ll be subject to a fine. Often, this date is the first of the month. Pay your rent on time, or you’ll face the consequences! A few landlords may be a bit more understanding and allow you to pay a few days late if you ask first… but the vast majority of them will expect the full payment on or before the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips for remembering to pay your rent on time: Set a calendar alert or reminder in your phone. Put a note on a physical calendar, white board, or on your fridge. Get into a habit of always checking with your roommates so you can remind each other to pay rent on time. Your landlord will appreciate it and will see you as a good, trustworthy tenant!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #3: Avoid Damaging the Property and You’ll Likely Get Your Deposit Back&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do your best to keep the property looking good. This is key if you want to get your deposit back! We get it: things break sometimes. Let’s say your doorknob falls off, or the dishwasher stops working. If something like that happens, get in touch with your landlord or property manager right away! They will likely send someone to fix it in the next day or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But try to avoid breaking or damaging things. If something is clearly your fault, it’s possible that you might not get your deposit back. For example, be careful not to scratch floors or walls when moving furniture. Don’t leave carpet stains untreated. And be honest if something gets damaged while you’re living there… your landlord will find out eventually, so it’s best to be upfront.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Be a Good Renter (and Get Your Deposit Back!)]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you’re trying to find a place to live, it’s very important that your landlord sees you as a good renter (aka tenant)! Unfortunately…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/how-to-be-a-good-renter-and-get-your-deposit-back/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/how-to-be-a-good-renter-and-get-your-deposit-back/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you’re trying to find a place to live, it’s very important that your landlord sees you as a good renter (aka tenant)! Unfortunately, there are landlords out there who don’t like to rent to college students. They may see students as irresponsible, messy, or prone to being late on rent payments. But you can prove them wrong with these tips on how to be a good renter! Bonus—you’ll get your security deposit back at the end of your lease term!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #1: Understand the Lease&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to read through the lease in order to understand it. Make sure you know the rules involved. Are pets prohibited? Don’t bring pets into your apartment. Do you have to take trash to the curb every Tuesday? Make sure to do that! Not allowed to have noisy parties? Go to the bar instead, or have a party at a friend’s house if their apartment allows it. Understand what is and isn’t allowed, and follow these rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you break the terms of the lease, you will show your landlord that you’re untrustworthy. If that happens, they’ll be less likely to be lenient if you mess up in the future. You may also have to pay hefty fines for breaking the rules. Worst case scenario: Breaking the terms of your lease could even lead to you being asked to leave your apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #2: Pay Your Rent on Time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice in your contract that you have to pay your rent by a certain date or you’ll be subject to a fine. Often, this date is the first of the month. Pay your rent on time, or you’ll face the consequences! A few landlords may be a bit more understanding and allow you to pay a few days late if you ask first… but the vast majority of them will expect the full payment on or before the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips for remembering to pay your rent on time: Set a calendar alert or reminder in your phone. Put a note on a physical calendar, white board, or on your fridge. Get into a habit of always checking with your roommates so you can remind each other to pay rent on time. Your landlord will appreciate it and will see you as a good, trustworthy tenant!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step #3: Avoid Damaging the Property and You’ll Likely Get Your Deposit Back&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do your best to keep the property looking good. This is key if you want to get your deposit back! We get it: things break sometimes. Let’s say your doorknob falls off, or the dishwasher stops working. If something like that happens, get in touch with your landlord or property manager right away! They will likely send someone to fix it in the next day or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But try to avoid breaking or damaging things. If something is clearly your fault, it’s possible that you might not get your deposit back. For example, be careful not to scratch floors or walls when moving furniture. Don’t leave carpet stains untreated. And be honest if something gets damaged while you’re living there… your landlord will find out eventually, so it’s best to be upfront.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 Tips for College Freshmen]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you heading off to college for the first time this fall? Being a college freshman is exciting, but it’s also a whole lot of new…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/12-tips-for-college-freshmen/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/12-tips-for-college-freshmen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Are you heading off to college for the first time this fall? Being a college freshman is exciting, but it’s also a whole lot of new experiences packed into one year, which can be stressful. Here are a few helpful tips for the first-time university student!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Making it to class on time might be a challenge, so be prepared!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, it’s generally easy to make it to class on time. You just have to walk from room to room between classes. But in college, it’s all too easy to forget, lose track of time, or sleep in. You’ll have to stay organized!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. You should get involved with some activities, but don’t let them affect your classwork.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are TONS of activities available at your college! Get involved! But remember, schoolwork comes first if you want to get good grades your freshman year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. You probably aren’t required to live in the dorms… living off-campus might be better!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some colleges require freshmen to live on campus, but others don’t. There are some huge benefits to living off campus! &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/blog/on-campus-vs-off-campus-housing/&quot;&gt;Here are a few&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. You’ll need to study twice as much as you think you do.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, many students can still get good grades with minimal studying. But the same isn’t true for most college classes: you’ll need to study. We know, you’ve heard it from your parents and teachers, but it’s true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Plagiarism is a BIG deal!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, your teachers and parents have probably told you to avoid plagiarism. Listen to them! Learn exactly how to avoid it. Failing to do so can have serious consequences on your college career and job opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6. Take extra care to stay healthy.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be tough to stay healthy when you move away from home for the first time. It’s your responsibility to eat healthy foods, exercise regularly, and reduce stress. If you don’t stay healthy, you’ll struggle to enjoy your freshman year and succeed in school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;7. Take advantage of help when you need it.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a rough time with your mental health? Struggling in a class? No matter your problem, there’s probably a whole system in place to help you out. Never be afraid to seek help—you don’t have to do things on your own!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;8. Try to meet new people.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether your high school friends are at your new college or not, you should work to build new relationships with your neighbors, classmates, and more. You might just find your new best friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;9. Build relationships with your professors.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to meeting other students, you’ll want to get to know your professors so they can assist you with schoolwork, internships and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;10. Get to know the town/city sooner rather than later.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get to know your new town: where to shop, where to hang out, where to get the best pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;11. Be a good roommate.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you live on campus or off-campus, you need to keep up a good relationship with your roommate(s). Be courteous and obey the golden rule!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;12. Make your new room/apartment feel like home.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decorate your new place in a way that makes you feel comfortable and relaxed. Your room should be your retreat from the stresses of college life.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 Reasons Why Living Off Campus is Fun and Easy!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trying to decide whether to live on campus or off? Here are some reasons why you should consider the off-campus life. Not only is it fun to…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/6-reasons-why-living-off-campus-is-fun-and-easy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/6-reasons-why-living-off-campus-is-fun-and-easy/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Trying to decide whether to live on campus or off? Here are some reasons why you should consider the off-campus life. Not only is it fun to live off campus, but it might be even easier than you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Living off campus gives you tons of freedom!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you live in the dorms, there are quite a few rules, and there’s an RA nearby at all times making sure you follow the rules. In a dorm, you’re limited when it comes to decorating, entertaining guests, and much more. Plus, you’ll probably have to share restrooms with your whole floor. But when living off campus, you get the freedom to stay up as late as you want, light candles when you want—in some cases you can even bring your pet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Living off-campus is often more affordable.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will get more freedom when it comes to choosing the apartment in the first place. Instead of getting assigned to a specific dorm room, you can choose the exact apartment you want to live in based on its location, amenities, size, and price. It is often the case that off campus housing is substantially more affordable than on-campus options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. You’ll often get more space compared to dorm living.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorm rooms are famously cramped and small, but off-campus housing gives you more options. If a larger living space is important to you, you can definitely find it. Of course, you’ll probably still need to get a roommate or a few—but you won’t be nearly as cramped. Also, off-campus options usually have more parking space for your car and your guests’ vehicles too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Many off-campus housing options have great amenities like pools or gyms.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of off-campus apartments have amenities located right in the building, such as swimming pools, fitness centers, common areas, and more. You might even get your own washer and dryer, which is super convenient for busy college students! If these things are important to you, you may want to consider the off-campus life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Off-campus housing is still close to your classes!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, you could potentially even be CLOSER to your classes when living off-campus—it all depends on the situation. Nearly every college or university has plenty of houses and apartments surrounding it, so if you want to be within walking distance, it isn’t a problem. Other cities are more spread out and it might take a few more minutes to get to campus—however, it may be totally worth it to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6. It’s easy to find great off-campus rentals that work for you.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Afito, you can search for the perfect off-campus apartment for your needs. We make it simple! Click here, enter your school name, and find a property. We make college renting simple so you don’t have to stress about finding a place!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Ways to Transform Your New Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you move into your new college housing, it’s probably a little bit bland and boring to start out. So, if you want it to really feel…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/5-ways-to-transform-your-new-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/5-ways-to-transform-your-new-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you move into your new college housing, it’s probably a little bit bland and boring to start out. So, if you want it to really feel like home, you’ll need to add a personal touch to it! When your apartment feels like home, you’re likely to feel more relaxed. You’ll have a nice place to retreat to after the stress of classes and studying, so your mental health won’t suffer as much. Plus, your friends will be impressed with your decorating skills! So here are 5 easy ways to transform your new apartment into a relaxing home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Make Your Bed Extra-Comfy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College is stressful, and you need your sleep! Put a little effort into making your bed a beautiful, comfy place to relax, whether that means getting a big cozy blanket in your favorite color or adding a few cute throw pillows for personality. If your mattress is uncomfortable, you can find mattress covers that amp up the comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Add Some Plants (Fake or Real!)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s just something about greenery that makes a home feel more relaxing and lively at the same time. If you feel like you can take care of a live plant, then visit a garden center and find some easy-to-care-for houseplants or succulents. Make sure to read the care instructions to see if you have enough sunlight for them, and make sure you’re able to water them appropriately (not too little and not too much). The benefit of live houseplants is that they can actually purify your indoor air, keeping you healthier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you don’t want the responsibility of keeping a living plant alive, there are some great-looking fake plants out there. You can find cute faux plants at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.target.com/&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ikea.com/us/en/&quot;&gt;IKEA&lt;/a&gt;, and many other stores, and they’ll make your apartment look beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Get a Rug or Two&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t always think about it, but the floor is probably one of the largest surfaces in your room or apartment. If you have bland beige carpet or tile, you might enjoy the softness, color, and pattern of a pretty rug underfoot. It’s a great way to inject a little more personality and comfort into your space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Add Some Wall Art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Print out photos, find pictures that you like online, hit up the thrift store, or even create some art on your own. It can be cheap and easy to decorate your new dorm room or apartment! Choose wall art that you truly enjoy and it’ll feel like home in no time. You don’t have to rush to put things up on your wall just for the sake of having art. Take the time to collect things you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Add Some Extra Lighting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some apartments, houses, and dorm rooms don’t have the best lighting. One top decor and home design tip is to have more than one source of light in each room. If you already have a bright overhead light, you’ll want a lamp or two to use in the evening. If your apartment is already dim, you might need to add a couple more lighting sources to keep it from looking like a cave.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[7 Things to Find Out Before You Rent an Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[1. Find out everything that’s included in the rent For example, you don’t want to move in and suddenly realize that your apartment doesn’t…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/7-things-to-find-out-before-you-rent-an-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/7-things-to-find-out-before-you-rent-an-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;1. Find out everything that’s included in the rent&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you don’t want to move in and suddenly realize that your apartment doesn’t come with a parking space for your car. And if you assume that certain utilities are included in your monthly rent, you might get sticker shock when you find out that you’re actually responsible for paying the electricity bill. When touring properties, you can ask the property manager what’s included. And always make sure to read through the rental contract and double-check everything before you sign!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Ask about the laundry situation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Busy students don’t have a lot of time to spend on laundry, so it’s important to make sure laundry is easy to do—you don’t want to have to take the bus across town to wash your socks! Are there washers and dryers in each apartment? Or are there shared ones in the building? If so, how much does it cost to do your laundry onsite? If there’s no laundry onsite, is there a good laundromat nearby? This is one of the most overlooked things that can really make a difference in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Find out if pets are allowed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you have a pet or not, it’s good to know whether or not pets are allowed. Some apartments won’t even let a visitor bring a pet—even if it’s just for a few minutes. So, find out how strict the rules are regarding pets. If you’re interested in getting a pet in the future, figure out what types are and aren’t allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Decide whether the apartment seems safe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to feel completely safe and comfortable in your own home, even if it’s just a rental. So, when you look at apartments, make sure that it’s someplace where you’d feel comfortable being alone at night. It should have good locks and security features such as outdoor lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Check to ensure the appliances, plumbing, etc. are well maintained&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, your first college apartment might not be super-luxurious—but your appliances, faucets, and toilets should definitely work properly. After all, you’re paying monthly rent for the ability to use these items. In a perfect world, you could assume that all these things work properly, but it doesn’t hurt to check before you move in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6. Check whether the apartment has heating, AC, etc.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your climate, some apartments might not have heating or AC. Since you want to be comfortable in every season, this is definitely something to take note of! Make sure you also know who’s responsible for paying the heating, electricity, and other utilities bills. Some apartments may include certain utilities in the monthly rent, while other apartments leave it up to the tenants to pay their utility bills separately from the monthly rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;7. Find out exactly how long it takes to get to class&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time yourself walking, driving, or taking public transportation to campus. You definitely want to know what you’re in for, especially if you’ll be on campus early in the morning or late at night. You don’t want your living situation to get in the way of your studies.
Hopefully these tips will help you find the best college apartment for your needs! Browse Afito to find the best college apartments in your area and start searching!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Best Apartments For Rowan Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[Searching for the perfect off campus apartment can be a tough process. If you’re on the hunt, we have good news for you- we’ve taken the…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/best-apartments-for-rowan-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/best-apartments-for-rowan-students/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Searching for the perfect off campus apartment can be a tough process. If you’re on the hunt, we have good news for you- we’ve taken the time to compile a complete list of the top apartments for Rowan students around Glassboro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/1670/&quot;&gt;Campus Terrace Apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One, and two bedroom apartments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campus Terrace Apartments are just about as close to campus as you can get. Just across the street from Rowan, this well-liked complex is known for attentive service and property management and affordable prices. Owned and managed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.depaulmanagementcompany.com/&quot;&gt;DePaul Management Company&lt;/a&gt;, which has been in the real estate business since 1946, Campus Terrace is a great option for any Rowan student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/675&quot;&gt;Park Crest Village&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Park Crest Village is a beautiful apartment complex close by to campus and a short walk to downtown Glassboro. The apartments feature large bedrooms and closets  as well as a private balcony or patio, and are available fully furnished upon request. The complex has plenty of parking and prides itself on excellent service to its tenants. Short term leases that cover only the school year are also available, which can save student renters a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/635&quot;&gt;The Crossings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Crossings at Glassboro is an amazing complex of student apartments located right next door to campus. The newly renovated apartments at The Crossings feature a plethora of lush amenities. Here you can find a turf volleyball court, a pool, a sauna, a fitness center, tanning beds, student workstations and a large club room and common area. What more could you possible need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/902/&quot;&gt;Holly Court&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Studio, one, and two bedroom apartments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holly Court is a beautiful complex located in Pitman, just minutes from the Rowan campus. The complex features modern apartments with private patios and balconies, a pool area/sundeck, and in-unit washers and dryers. These apartments are also within walking distance to Alcyon Lake Park. Rowan students are sure to find a relaxing lifestyle at Holly Court!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/1060/&quot;&gt;Essex Chase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two and three bedroom apartments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brand new Essex Chase apartments offer a true luxury living experience just down the street from Rowan University. Tenants will find beautifully designed community areas as well as state of the art fitness and pool facilities. Newly built units feature nine foot ceilings, granite countertops, top of the line appliances, and full size washers and dryers. Essex Chase also offers some pet friendly units, and even features a dog park!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/973/&quot;&gt;Uptown Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Private rooms in a shared space&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uptown Commons is an innovative shared living community in Pitman, close by to campus. Student tenants live in their own private rooms and share bathrooms and other common areas. The space is newly renovated, and furnished units are available upon request. Utilities and Wi-Fi are included in the rent. Uptown Commons is a great option for budget conscious students looking for a community environment off campus.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Top Landlords at SUNY Cortland]]></title><description><![CDATA[Searching around to find great landlords at SUNY Cortland can be a time-consuming task, especially if you’re moving off campus for the first…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/top-landlords-at-suny-cortland/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/top-landlords-at-suny-cortland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Searching around to find great landlords at SUNY Cortland can be a time-consuming task, especially if you’re moving off campus for the first time. No one wants to find themselves in a less than desirable living situation while working their way through school. Thankfully, we at Afito have gotten to know almost every college landlord in the area. Here’s our list of the best landlords at SUNY Cortland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/252&quot;&gt;Gary Baccile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary Baccile has been renting to students in the Cortland area for the past eight years. With the help of his maintenance specialist Kip Fox, who has over thirty years of experience in property management, Gary owns and manages seven student rentals around town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/253&quot;&gt;Ithacor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ithacor is a local property management company serving Cortland as well as several other cities and towns in the area. They work with area property owners to manage their rental houses efficiently and effectively, and have over fifteen years of experience in the space. They are well known for being responsive and accommodating to tenant concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/224&quot;&gt;Calabro Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calabro Properties offers many housing options to student tenants, all of which are a quick walk to campus and downtown. Single person one bedroom apartments all the way up to houses for large groups of 9+ students are available. Each and every apartment is fully furnished and recently renovated, with such amenities as flat screen televisions, in-unit laundry facilities, and snow removal services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/275&quot;&gt;SV Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SV Student rentals is an experienced SUNY Cortland student landlord offering everything from small one bedroom apartments to large 12 bedroom houses. Each property is located within walking distance from campus and downtown. All units are fully furnished and feature included garbage pickup, parking, laundry, and high speed internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/233&quot;&gt;Marc Pace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Pace has been renting to Cortland students for more than 25 years! Marc takes pride in his houses and has each one refurbished and professionally inspected every year. All of his properties are a short walk to campus. Tenants tend to be very happy with Marc and feel that he goes above and beyond as a landlord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/237&quot;&gt;Cortland Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Student Rentals, owned and operated by Mark’s brother Keith Pace, has been managing off-campus housing in Cortland since 1979. They take pride in being a local landlord and improving the community in which they live and do business. Tenants can expect a responsive landlord with people on-call around the clock. All units are well furnished and close by to campus and downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/225&quot;&gt;Michael Pace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not often that you see three brothers at the same school offering great student rental properties. Michael Pace brings forty years of experience in student housing to his properties at Cortland. All units are fully furnished and feature free parking and snow/trash removal. Utilities are included in the rent for most units!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/247&quot;&gt;Paradigm Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradigm Properties has been in the SUNY Cortland off campus housing business since 1981. The company strives to provide the highest quality student housing, and pays particular attention to the smart design of its units for student tenants. Paradigm maintains a full-time property manager and maintenance staff and is on call around the clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/232&quot;&gt;Armideo Student Housing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The father-son team behind Armideo Student Housing offers a large number of great student housing options in the Cortland area. Joe Armideo has been renting to students since 1972 and boasts that if your parents went to Cortland, he probably knew them. Apartments feature on-site laundry and new kitchen and bathroom facilities, and parking and snow removal are included in the rent. Unlike some area landlords, Armideo Student Housing allows for rent to be paid monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/246&quot;&gt;Cortland Off Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serving the SUNY Cortland and TC3 communities for over 30 years, Cortland Off Campus offers some of the best student rentals around. Units are close by to campus as well as downtown and are fully furnished (including with leather couches and large flat-screen televisions.) 24/7 staff are available around the clock for every tenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/288&quot;&gt;Collegetown Rentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collegetown Rentals offers many student rental properties at SUNY Cortland, each close by to campus, downtown, and the athletic complexes. All units are fully furnished and feature all-in rental rates which include utilities, laundry, and snow removal. Maintenance staff are on call 24/7 to respond to any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/278&quot;&gt;Walk2Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk2Campus has been providing off campus housing since 2004. They strive to maintain beautiful rental units within walking distance to campus and are particularly proud of their values-driven approach to property management. Walk2Campus is committed to leaving a positive impact on the environment and using the most sustainable methods possible to operate their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/279&quot;&gt;RMP Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RMP Properties has been in the Cortland off campus housing business since 2003. RMP strives to make student tenants’ lives as easy as possible by providing affordable and all inclusive rental properties. All units are close to campus and are designed to have a positive impact on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/301&quot;&gt;JE Management Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JE Management group provides a variety of houses and apartments near SUNY Cortland and TC3. With over twenty years experience in the business, student tenants can rest assured that they will have an easy leasing and renting experience with JE Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/280&quot;&gt;Working on a Dream Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living by the motto “You work on your dream…we work on the rest,” Working on a Dream Properties provides affordable, high quality student housing just a short walk from campus and downtown. The company features an on-call local manager as well as included utilizes for all units. Working on a Dream places a specific emphasis on providing clean and well-maintained houses and apartments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the unlikely event that you can’t find your home away from home from these outstanding landlords in the SUNY Cortland area, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/area/6&quot;&gt;check out Afito&lt;/a&gt; to see the rest of the available listings near campus. If you would prefer living in an apartment building, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.afito.com/best-apartments-for-cortland-students/&quot;&gt;check out our article on the best apartments for Cortland students.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Best Apartments For Cortland Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[We all know that finding a great off campus apartment can be a hassle. But don’t worry! Lucky for you we’ve already done a lot of the…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/best-apartments-for-cortland-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/best-apartments-for-cortland-students/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We all know that finding a great off campus apartment can be a hassle. But don’t worry! Lucky for you we’ve already done a lot of the research on your behalf. Behold the top student apartments in the Cortland area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/246&quot;&gt;Cortland Off Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, three, and four bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Off Campus has been managing student rentals around SUNY Cortland for more than 30 years. Their buildings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/534&quot;&gt;90 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/545&quot;&gt;19 W. Court St&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/537&quot;&gt;88 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt; offer well-managed, fully furnished, and conveniently located places to live for Cortland students. Cortland Off Campus also owns and manages several smaller buildings and single family homes that are also available as student rentals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/602&quot;&gt;8 Lincoln Ave.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right in the middle of the action in downtown Cortland and a super quick walk to campus, 8 Lincoln Ave. is a unique apartment building with a community feel. Perfect for students moving out of the dorms, this building features plenty of parking as well as free utilities and WiFi. The building is owned and managed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/275&quot;&gt;SV Student Rentals&lt;/a&gt;, a well-established Cortland landlord that also rents many smaller buildings and homes in the area to student tenants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/257&quot;&gt;Cornerstone Properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cornerstone Properties, a 35 year veteran of the Cortland residential housing market, offers new and spacious three bedroom suites at several locations around Cortland, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/570&quot;&gt;112 Groton Ave.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/575&quot;&gt;100 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/573&quot;&gt;50 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/574&quot;&gt;52 Tompkins St.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/571&quot;&gt;7 Woodruff St.&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/572&quot;&gt;91 Lincoln Ave.&lt;/a&gt;. All of these locations are a walkable distance from campus and downtown. Units are fully furnished and include free WiFi and parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/634&quot;&gt;41 Prospect Terrace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two and three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;41 Prospect Terrace, owned by the aptly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/299&quot;&gt;Campus Side Apartments LLC&lt;/a&gt;, is as close to campus as you can get. The building features fully renovated and fully furnished two and three bedroom apartments that are just a quick walk to downtown Cortland. 41 Prospect is a perfect option for students moving out of the dorms who want to stay as close as possible to everything happening on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/632&quot;&gt;College Suites at Cortland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, three, and four bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College Suites at Cortland is a new building jam-packed with luxury amenities, located just outside the city of Cortland. Just a few minutes drive from downtown, College Suites features free parking, media rooms, fitness centers, game rooms, and a basketball court. The brand new apartments are fully furnished and come with free WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/631&quot;&gt;Cortland Park Apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, two, and three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located just across the Tioughnioga River at 44 Rickard St., Cortland Park Apartments is a beautiful apartment complex featuring a relaxing outdoor pool and over five acres of beautifully maintained grounds, as well as tennis and basketball courts. Just 5 minutes from SUNY Cortland and a quick walk into downtown, Cortland Park is a perfect option for students looking for beautiful surroundings and a quieter living arrangement that is still close to all the happenings downtown and on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/628&quot;&gt;Village Terrace&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/627&quot;&gt;Country Townhomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located just outside the city of Cortland, these adjacent apartment complexes feature a beautiful park-like setting that is just a quick stroll away from the Professional Studies Building and the athletics fields. These homey units are perfect for serious students seeking a quieter place to live. Both complexes are owned by Cortland-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/landlord/282&quot;&gt;DLH Properties&lt;/a&gt;, which has been operating in the area since 1989.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/633&quot;&gt;Cortland Campus View&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortland Campus View at 211 Tompkins Street is a charming building featuring three bedroom apartments that is situated right across the street from SUNY Cortland. The building is very close to the School of Professional Studies, the Stadium Complex, and Lusk Fieldhouse, making it an excellent choice for student athletes and professional studies students. Units are fully furnished and feature free WiFi and utilities included in the cost of rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/property/629&quot;&gt;Stevens Manor Apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One and two bedroom apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stevens Manor Apartments at 10 Homestead Drive offers affordable one and two bedroom units that are a quick walk to the athletics fields and Professional Studies building. Perfect for athletes and professional studies students, Stevens Manor offers some of the most affordable rents in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this information will help make your hunt for off campus student housing at SUNY Cortland a bit easier. If you’re still having trouble finding your perfect home, &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com/area/6&quot;&gt;click here to see what’s available around campus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Tips for Picking the Perfect Off-Campus Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Picking an off-campus apartment is not an easy task. There are lots of factors that you need to take into consideration when making this…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/5-tips-for-picking-the-perfect-off-campus-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/5-tips-for-picking-the-perfect-off-campus-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Picking an off-campus apartment is not an easy task. There are lots of factors that you need to take into consideration when making this type of decision because one wrong move could cost you hundreds of extra dollars a month. And nobody wants that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is we’ve put together 5 tips for picking the perfect off-campus apartment so you can enjoy these fun (and hopefully, educational!) years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. First, Make a Budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you even start looking for an apartment, the first thing you should do is make a budget of what you can afford to pay for rent each month. One of the biggest mistakes students make when signing their first lease is getting something they can’t afford. The last thing you want to worry about is scraping up enough money each month to make rent. Be proactive, find out what you’re able to spend each month, and stick to it! You may not get the gorgeous apartment of your dreams on a college budget, but a smaller apartment or an extra few minutes walk to campus is probably better than going a year without any spending money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Take Some Tours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t just look at one apartment or housing unit. Take the time to set up multiple apartment tours and have a clear understanding of what options you have. Our advice: pick your top three off-campus living options and go tour them all. That way when it comes time to make a decision, you’ve seen everything firsthand and won’t have to worry about any surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Location, Location, Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a student means you need to spend a lot of time on campus. Whether you’re studying in the library, taking classes, or just hanging out with friends, much of your time will be spent there. So location is an important factor to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s not located within walking distance of your class buildings, is there a bus stop nearby that can take you to class? What about other transportation opportunities? Make sure that no matter where you end up you have an easy, convenient and hopefully free way to get where you need to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Grab Some Roomies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If at all possible, get some roommates. Living with other college students can make rent and utilities cheaper and more affordable. Find people who are looking for a similar living situation as you are and find a place together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When signing a lease, make sure everyone is there and that everyone signs the lease. Depending on your lease agreement you want to make sure that if someone breaks the lease that they can be held accountable for their share of the rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Read Your Lease, Seriously!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of leases, before signing your name- read the lease! Your name is going on a legal document which means that you can be held liable for violating any of its provbisions. Take the fifteen minutes to read the lease, make sure you understand it, and then sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, make a budget, shop around, pay attention to the location, get some roommates, and read your lease. There you go- 5 simple things that you can do to help make your apartment hunting experience easier and more successful. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Things You Need to Know Before Signing a Lease for an Apartment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s say you’re speaking with an owner of an off-campus apartment complex. Everything sounds great and the apartment is in decent shape…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/3-things-you-need-to-know-before-signing-a-lease-for-an-apartment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/3-things-you-need-to-know-before-signing-a-lease-for-an-apartment/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’re speaking with an owner of an off-campus apartment complex. Everything sounds great and the apartment is in decent shape, then the owner turns to you and asks “Do you have any questions?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if you’re a first-time apartment hunter, knowing what questions to ask in these situations can be tricky. Lucky for you, we’ve got a list of the top questions to ask a landlord before agreeing to sign a lease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“What, exactly, is included in my rent?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, you want to know what you’re paying for. To make the right decision on an apartment, you need to have a clear understanding of what’s included in your rent. Are there any utilities included in your rent (water, heat, electricity, etc.)? What about amenities? Do you get free access to a clubhouse or workout room with your rent costs? What about parking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might surprise you how much is actually included in your rent costs, so it’s important that you ask the question. It can really influence your decision one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also find it helpful to have a set of things written out that you want or need your rent to cover. (For example, you might need in-house laundry facilities or a garage space for your car, or you might really want a gym/exercise room). If the owner doesn’t mention something on your list, ask about it and see if that’s an additional cost you will have to pick up somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“How much does the average utility bill cost?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to think that when you sign a lease to an apartment, the only cost you have to worry about paying is rent. While rent is the main cost, you will also need to keep in mind that you will have to pay a monthly utility bill as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the area, the time of year, the size of the apartment, and the energy efficiency of its appliances (oh, and how good you are at turning off the lights!) utility bills can range from as low as $20 to as high as $100. The only way to really get a feel for what you might have to pay is to ask apartment owner what the average utility bill costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Are there any additional fees?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a college student, you are typically living on a tight budget as it is. You’re going to want to make sure that there won’t be any extra fees that pop up. Ask the owner if there will be a signing fee, processing/application fee, subleasing fee, approval fee or anything else. Be on the lookout for fees like these because it can add up quickly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, these questions will help you in your decision-making process and give you a better idea of what you want from an apartment or housing unit. Best of luck with your apartment search!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[4 Important Apartment Hunting Tips for Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[Renting your first off-campus apartment is an exciting milestone, but it can also be a huge source of stress if you are unprepared. Whether…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/4-important-apartment-hunting-tips-for-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/4-important-apartment-hunting-tips-for-students/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Renting your first off-campus apartment is an exciting milestone, but it can also be a huge source of stress if you are unprepared. Whether you are moving out of your parents’ house or seeking alternatives to on-campus housing, there are several things you should know before you begin your student housing search. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Your Search Early&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-Campus housing can be the best student housing option for many, but it can be difficult to find off-campus apartments if you’re not proactive in your search. It is recommended to start your search for student housing 8-12 months in advance for areas with a highly competitive rental market. For areas that are not as competitive, 2-6 months is recommended. Begin your student housing search as early as possible to avoid competing with other students seeking off-campus living arrangements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take Advantage of Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure where to begin your search for student housing, there are several resources available. First, check if &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com&quot;&gt;Afito.com&lt;/a&gt; has listings for your school — Afito only lists rentals designed for students. If your school isn’t on there, that’s okay too. Most universities offer off-campus living services. It is also possible to find local listings in the newspaper or by driving around campus looking for rental signs. However, the best place to begin your student housing search is online. If your school isn’t on &lt;a href=&quot;https://afito.com&quot;&gt;Afito.com&lt;/a&gt;, other listing sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zillow.com&quot;&gt;Zillow.com&lt;/a&gt; may have some student housing options and can connect you with landlords near your school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plan Your Budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for student housing, consider your living costs to see whether the rent will fit into your budget. This way, you won’t make the mistake of signing a lease on an apartment you can’t afford. The general rule of thumb is that your monthly income should be three times your monthly rent, although your situation may be different depending on if you receive aid from your parents or other sources.
If affordable student housing is your goal, planning your budget in advance is an effective way to determine if off-campus living is right for you. Planning your budget before your student housing search can help you decide where you can cut costs and how many roommates you will need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Distance is Key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proximity to campus can greatly affect the cost of rent. The closer to campus a property is, the higher the rent is likely going to be. If you have access to a vehicle, the best option for affordable student housing is looking for properties in neighboring towns. Living just 10-15 minute from campus can save you up to hundreds a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also take into account your daily commute; your distance from classes and other on-campus activities can greatly affect your experience with off-campus living. If you can find an off-campus apartment within walking distance from classes, a grocery store, and anything else you will need, you can forgo the added cost of fuel or car insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On-Campus VS Off-Campus Housing]]></title><description><![CDATA[College is different for everybody and your experience will greatly differ depending on where you choose to live. While some may prefer the…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/on-campus-vs-off-campus-housing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/on-campus-vs-off-campus-housing/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;College is different for everybody and your experience will greatly differ depending on where you choose to live. While some may prefer the community aspect of living on-campus, others may prefer the independence of living off-campus. When looking at student housing options, the choice you make can affect your entire college experience, therefore it’s important to consider the best student housing options for your situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living in on-campus housing&lt;/strong&gt; can be a great way to build your social circle and be involved in campus life.  In most cases, you will be in close proximity to everything else on campus such as: your classes, the dining hall, libraries, and the student center. Most campuses also provide transportation services that make it easy to get around campus. On-campus housing is often considered to be the best option for incoming freshmen and is sometimes mandated by the school for underclassmen.
However, for most on-campus housing options, there are rules and regulations you have to follow. Infringement of these rules can often lead to suspension or expulsion from the residence hall or even the university. On top of strict regulations, campus housing can often be expensive and may not be the most affordable student housing option. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living off-campus&lt;/strong&gt; is a great idea for those seeking more private student housing options and can be an attractive alternative for those seeking independence from the commotion of campus life. Off-campus housing is often cheaper than living on-campus and is the best student housing option for upperclassmen who wish to focus on their studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for off-campus living arrangements it’s important to consider the safety of the neighborhood as well as the proximity to campus. It’s also important to know what to look for in a landlord when looking at off-campus housing options. Because off-campus housing isn’t owned by the school, make sure to be aware of local ordinances and other regulations set by the township. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While off-campus housing can seem like the easy choice, it comes with responsibilities. On top of rent and utilities, renters generally spend more time grocery-shopping, preparing meals, cleaning, and commuting. Despite these obligations, living off-campus offers even more freedom than you would get from living in a residence hall. At the same time, it helps with the transition to life after college by acclimating you to responsibilities like house maintenance, rent, and other bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both on- and off-campus housing have their benefits and drawbacks. It’s up to you to weigh the pros and cons and figure out the best student housing option for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Get the Most Out of Your Afito Listing]]></title><description><![CDATA[The way landlords advertise their rental properties has changed a lot over the past decade. Fortunately for today’s property owners, in 201…]]></description><link>localhost:8000/how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-afito-listing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">localhost:8000/how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-afito-listing/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The way landlords advertise their rental properties has changed a lot over the past decade. Fortunately for today’s property owners, in 2019 this process can be as easy as posting your vacancies on a popular listing platform. College landlords however need to be especially mindful of the expectations prospective student tenants have when searching for their off-campus home. Here are a few pointers on how to separate your listing from the rest of the pack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your main photo is your first impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting clear, high quality photographs of the front of your rentals is the first step to a great listing. Listings with visually appealing, high-resolution photographs tend to catch students’ attention as they scroll through potential homes and apartments. Don’t balk at hiring a professional to photograph your properties- the expense is likely to pay dividends for years to come whenever you advertise vacancies online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The more pictures, the better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students want to see as many high quality pictures as they can when researching housing options. College tenants like to see pictures that reflect a properties cleanliness as well as its physical features. If you don’t currently have photographs of the interiors of your properties, we recommend having them taken (or taking them yourself) the next time your leases turn over, before your new tenants move in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thorough Descriptions are key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students want to know as much as possible before reaching out to a landlord. If information about a listing is lacking, many prospective tenants will simply move on to a more informative listing. Some topics students love to see in listing descriptions are: what amenities are offered, what kind of parking is available, whether any bills or utilities are included, and details about the occupancy of the house (how many singles, doubles, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strike a professional tone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College kids, who are usually new to living on their own, want responsive, reliable landlords that they feel will ensure a smooth and pleasant off-campus living experience. Student tenants respond well to landlords who are organized, respond quickly to inquiries, and take care to communicate in a professional and friendly matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Placement matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No surprises here- students are more likely to see and respond to listings that appear at the top of the listing search feed. Afito offers an innovative premium listings leaderboard that allows landlords to pay a monthly fee to launch their listing to the top ranks of the search results for their University. While this is a great way to increase exposure, landlords must be mindful that getting your property to the top is only half the battle- the listing itself must be attractive to your audience in order for them to click on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Afito team is happy to help our customers improve the quality and reach of their listings. If you need help, or have other any questions or concerns, shoot us an email at support@afito.com. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>